<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Omicron Citizen Series</title><description>Ruminations on music, coding and growing pains.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.11</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 18:15:51 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Back for the First Time</title><description>A blog post on starting out as a music producer and picking the right tools to make beats. First things first. Start. </description><link>http://localhost:2368/back-for-the-first-time/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">578d4266-3022-4cb5-ba29-fdaf4ac7d230</guid><category>Getting Started</category><category>producing</category><category>new producers</category><category>hardware and gear</category><dc:creator>Vainglorious</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 16:51:09 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/03/wesley-caribe-63610.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/03/wesley-caribe-63610.jpg" alt="Back for the First Time"&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you begin studying a new craft that you want to practice, it can be hard to distinguish between the tools you need to get the job done and "convenience" tools that are used make your life easier. It's something I definitely struggled with as a new producer so I want to put this out there for producers that will be new after me. &lt;br&gt;
I have no doubt you have heard the quote, "The journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step." I actually may have paraphrased a little but my point is, you have to start. You can't start the journey if you want to finish another mixing article, top 10 [insert item] list or watch one more tutorial on something you haven't even tried yet. You also can't start if you're trying to save up for that new piece of gear with the amazing tech that you've been following the development of for months now. &lt;br&gt;
And even seasoned craftspeople that don't have everything they'd &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; to have sometimes need reminders, too.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell me if you've seen this before on Snapchat, Instagram, YouTube or wherever you do your social media thing: &lt;br&gt;
Studio monitors - $700 &lt;br&gt;
Video monitor(s) - $200+ &lt;br&gt;
MIDI Keyboard - $150 &lt;br&gt;
Monitor stands - $75 &lt;br&gt;
Audio Interface - $300 &lt;br&gt;
Desk - $100  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generalization: Pros use outboard gear and other hardware.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many pros have (or use at their studio) hardware compressors and reverbs, large format consoles and all manner of cool looking gadget; none of which is &lt;strong&gt;needed&lt;/strong&gt; to start. And the keyword there is &lt;em&gt;start&lt;/em&gt;. Based on my research and personal experience, the reasons for outboard gear can be condensed to really 4 main things: &lt;br&gt;
  - familiarity &lt;br&gt;
  - workflow enhancement/save time &lt;br&gt;
  - pleasure &lt;br&gt;
  - specialty (getting that "certain sound" or "x factor")  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of that is necessary to begin. Literally. All you truly need is the software (DAW) and a way to hear what you're making. Now you might be thinking how to pick a DAW or which DAW is best. Before you Google that, let me save you some time here: there is no perfect DAW. There's no best DAW. There's no DAW with "the best" sound. There's only the right tool at the right time. What's perfect for you now may not be a fit down the line or may not work for you for a given task.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally I use Ableton. I love it and I do everything in it, but I've had to realize that it does have its shortcomings. While it's great for sketching and composition there are DAWs that do a better job with vocal comping and mixing, for example.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what's the answer then? What do you need to start? You need patience, resolve and creativity. Decide what you're creating and pick a DAW. Then pick another if you need to; I'm not judging. Find your fit. Discover how you like to work and find the program that offers you the least resistance.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think about it two ways: you have more time than you have money or you have more money than you have time. If you have more time than money then you should take the time to learn your DAW because it can do nearly anything that can be accomplished with hardware. If you have more money than time then get one or two things that will improve your workflow or efficiency. This might come in the form of improved sound via studio monitors or improved ergonomics in your studio or pretty much anything you can think of that will increase productivity.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, the gear doesn't make the music. You do. Tools are just tools at the end of the day. They're instruments for doing your work. Don't get lost in response curves and specs on rack mount reverbs and other wild internet rabbit holes. Whatever you pick, however you decide to configure things, the sounds that come out of it all come down to you creating and shaping them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make the music. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>One Hurdle at a Time</title><description>Recently I put my first beat up for sale on BeatStars. On Monday I released my first beat video for that beat on YouTube. Trials and tribulations, y'all.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/one-hurdle-at-a-time/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">c84820c3-8bb4-4033-bd14-f34f7b358889</guid><category>video editing</category><category>beat video</category><category>problem solving</category><category>troubleshooting</category><category>adobe</category><category>premiere pro</category><category>after effects</category><category>beatmaking</category><category>youtube</category><category>networking</category><dc:creator>Vainglorious</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/03/leandro-puca-184754.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/03/leandro-puca-184754.jpg" alt="One Hurdle at a Time"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This past week, I've been pondering the usefulness of YouTube because it's incredibly difficult to break through to a wide audience at this point but I did find myself using it to be seen on other people's videos and kind of start building out a network with other producers. With that in mind, I figure once I've done enough networking, people will start coming to my channel and it might be a bit weird for them to find it empty. So yesterday finds me making my first beat video for YouTube.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And... to summarize, painful is the first word I can think of. Seriously. I opened the video editor, having only used it briefly for looping or chopping shorter videos together. My first thought is, "well, what do I start with?" I didn't have stock footage. I didn't have anything original so I picked an action-packed episode of this anime. Why anime? Well, I'm a nerd and I love anime and I was hoping to create something that would hold people's attention. My beats are experimental; give me a break. Turns out I really have no idea what I'm doing. I'm looking up shortcuts and how to's for simple stuff every few minutes because I am just lost. Not to mention the mini meltdowns from frustration and sleepiness. Don't even get me started on scrubbing 30 minutes of video for good stuff to use; sometimes there wasn't enough and at other times, I had to make some tough decisions on what would stay. I didn't want to use sequences that were too long lest I call forth the mighty Copyright Strike Hammer of YouTube upon myself. Nobody wants that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I mention that it's probably already past midnight at that point in my struggle? The night before I was up until at least 3:30am drinking with my family. My nephew had his second birthday party but it was a Saturday so after the kids went down, the adults elected to have some fun, too. So I'm drinking and drinking. By the time I'm ready to go, I'm toasted. But the night is over. I can lay in my bed and get some shut-eye. Sweet. This was a good day.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost. I wake up 9 hours later extremely dehydrated but I say to myself you know I can drink some water, take some Advil and power through it. I've been trying to flesh out this video idea for a week so now it's time for some execution. Needless to say, I am lagging. I barely get anything done. Finally, I go down for a nap and I sleep until like 10:45 that night; maybe later. I get up like holy crap what time is it? The video. I haven't done &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; really. So back to working on the video; past midnight already. &lt;br&gt;
I'm getting toward the end and I start to feel accomplished until I remember I haven't even touched the FX program &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; my video was too short when I added the audio playback. So I'm going in trying to quickly add time without messing up my sequence. Okay, 6 seconds left to fill. I can see the light at the end of the tunnel! And I make it but then I remember I didn't leave room for an intro. /headdesk/  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had to look up encoder settings for YouTube and watch a few videos. &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Tvlmf2VJu8Q"&gt;Tim&lt;/a&gt; was extremely helpful.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encoding. It's 4am now. I have to be up and at 'em at 9 so I can make an appointment at 10. Probably pushing that back. And just when I think I can relax because I've gotten something done, I remember all the other stuff that goes into a song release. I've gotta write a description and decide on some tags, but not too many but with terms that aren't too broad either. I got a thumbnail to adjust (shoutout Foreign for the template). &lt;br&gt;
I have to say, it was an ordeal. But I'm glad I got through it and I do have my video to show for it plus the experience for future videos. I'll be that much faster next time. But alas, old habits as they say. It's 6:31am (the following day; or is it 2 days later now? I might be delirious) and I haven't been to bed yet. What is my life?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, you've suffered enough. Here's the video. Don't judge me. I'm terrible at "typing" but I'm working on it.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k8-iGtw1Vb4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's so much that goes into being a one man operation. If there are any beatmakers (or video makers) reading this, please share. How did your first video go? If you have any questions or tips, definitely let me know!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time. Don't be a stranger though.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>